<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Central Florida Real Estate Video Blog with Tammie Pickard</title>
    <description>Our mission at Team Central Florida is to be your best resource for Central Florida real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Team Central Florida, your professional Central Florida Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 15:36:53 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 15:36:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Central Florida Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-Z_QEVuf3ug?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the current state of our Central Florida market? What does it mean for you? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, our market favors sellers, which means we have less than five months’ worth of inventory. If six months of available inventory indicates a balanced market, seven months or more would signal that we are in a buyer’s market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, &lt;strong&gt;our current level of inventory stands at 3.6 months’ worth.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, it would take 3.6 months to sell off all the homes we have on our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Sellers are in the driver’s seat with our present market conditions, but that’s not to say there aren’t good opportunities for buyers as well.%20http://localhost:4000/your-central-florida-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Sellers are in the driver’s seat with our present market conditions, but that’s not to say there aren’t good opportunities for buyers as well.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as prices go, we’re actually seeing some increases. Three factors are driving market activity at the moment: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest rates&lt;/strong&gt; are currently at phenomenal lows, and would-be buyers are flocking to our market while homes are ripe for the picking.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rising prices.&lt;/strong&gt; On average, home prices have gone up by 6.3% year over year. Along with our low-interest-rate environment, buyers planning their upcoming retirement are deciding that now’s the time to act. They realize if they wait another five or six years, they could end up paying 30% to 50% more for their home purchase.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hose same baby boomer buyers are looking to buy and rent their property out now and move in later&lt;/strong&gt; to cover their expenses, lock in a favorable price, and still meet their homeownership goals upon retirement. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To recap, sellers are in the driver’s seat with our present market conditions, but that’s not to say there aren’t good opportunities for buyers as well. If you’re a serious buyer, your offer will most likely need to come in at list price right from the outset. With our help, you’ll be able to find the right home, negotiate the right price, and get into the home when it best suits your situation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how you can benefit from today’s market, please don’t hesitate to get in touch with us. We look forward to serving you in the future!&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-central-florida-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/your-central-florida-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Questions Should Homebuyers Be Asking?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GltaXyos6-0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to be going over a few important questions that every house hunter should be asking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. “How is the neighborhood or area?&lt;/strong&gt; We get a lot of questions about how close homes are to I-75, major airports, and traffic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What amenities are included in 55+ communities?&lt;/strong&gt; Many people want to be in these communities because they are maintenance-free and host awesome daily and weekly social activities in the community. You barely have to walk out your front door to have a good time in some places, but it’s definitely something that you’ll want to know about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A lot of 55+ communities are maintenance-free.%20http://localhost:4000/what-questions-should-homebuyers-be-asking.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A lot of 55+ communities are maintenance-free.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What fees will you have when buying a home?&lt;/strong&gt; Potential expenses could include your HOA fees, CDD fee, and flood insurance. CDDs come with a majority of neighborhoods and can increase your taxes. As for flood insurance, you definitely want to determine whether you’re in a flood zone or not. You might have a monthly maintenance fee if you are living in one of the maintenance-free communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for joining us today. If you have any questions or comments for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-questions-should-homebuyers-be-asking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-questions-should-homebuyers-be-asking.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To Our Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our market remains busy, and it’s still an opportune time to command a high price selling your home.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**We know what’s happening in Central Florida, specifically pertaining to home values, that will directly affect you. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we’ll be posting two monthly video messages on this blog to keep you updated.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will be valuable and useful in helping you stay on top of what’s happening in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check back because content will be coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to keep you updated on what’s happening in Central Florida!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-our-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-our-blog.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
